next few three syntax is best taught by looking at a code example
接下来的三种语法最好通过查看代码示例来学习
here you can see the template with a search input box
在这里您可以看到带有搜索输入框的模板
when we search
当我们搜索的时候
wanted to return the number of event results
想要返回事件结果的数量
the script tag we need to import draft because will have some reactive references
我们需要导入draft的脚本标记，因为它将有一些反应式引用
I will import the event a p I
我将导入事件a p I
this is just a dummy a p I threw together for the example
这只是一个虚拟的p，我把它放在一起作为例子
inside of our set at method we have our search input and our results for
在set at方法中，我们有搜索输入和结果
our reactive references remember we're just returning the number of results not the actual
我们的反应式引用记住我们只是返回结果的数量，而不是实际的结果
will call our event a p I
将我们的活动称为p I
ending in the search input value I'm returning the results
以搜索输入值结尾我返回结果
and finally since we need these inside of our template
最后，因为我们需要这些在模板中
returned both search input
返回了两个搜索输入
and results
结果呢
active references
活动引用
if we jump in our browser
如果我们进入浏览器
I'll see that this doesn't
我看这不会
not at all
一点也不
is that with our current code
这是我们目前的代码吗
are you can I call only gets called once
你能不能我只打一次电话
and setup is initially run
安装程序开始运行
and we needed to run every time the search input changes
我们需要在每次搜索输入改变时运行
this is where we need to use the watch effect syntax
这就是我们需要使用监视效果语法的地方
which is new for view three
对于视图3来说这是新的
important
重要的
barcode in a callback
回调中的条形码
watch effect will run this function on next tick
“监视效果”将在下一个刻度上运行此函数
re actively tracking its dependencies
重新主动跟踪其依赖项
rerunning it when its dependencies change
当依赖项更改时重新运行它
if we look in our browser now
如果我们现在查看浏览器
as we type
当我们打字时
a number of events gets updated
许多事件得到更新
you can think of watch effect
你可以想到手表效应
a simpler version of the watch
更简单的手表
auction that you might be familiar with from view too
你可能从视图中熟悉的拍卖
I still use the watch function when we want to be specific about what triggers the watcher to run
我仍然使用watch函数，当我们想具体说明什么触发观察程序运行时
even if I call back includes other reactive objects
即使我回叫也包括其他反应对象
won't get called unless search input changes
除非搜索输入更改，否则不会调用
watch we can also get access to the new value and old value of the item being watched
我们还可以访问被监视项目的新值和旧值
like you see here
就像你在这里看到的
I can watch multiple reactive objects
我可以看到多个反应对象
sending in an array
在数组中发送
you can also get access to the new and old values of each of these
您还可以访问这些值的新值和旧值
if we need them in our callback function
如果我们在回调函数中需要它们
what might it look like if we use watch instead of watch effect in our example
如果在我们的例子中使用手表而不是手表效果会是什么样子
we imported
我们进口的
called watch
叫手表
input
输入
because we want to run the callback when search input changes
因为我们希望在搜索输入更改时运行回调
if we looked at this in the browser
如果我们在浏览器中查看
you would notice
你会注意到的
number of events starts out as empty
事件数以空开始
then it works as we type
然后我们打字的时候就可以了
started out as MT because it didn't get run on initial load
一开始是MT，因为它没有在初始负载下运行
in other words watch
换句话说，观察
is lazy loaded by default
默认为延迟加载
might be the functionality you want
可能是你想要的功能
however if you did want to use watch
但是如果你真的想用手表
have it run on initial load
让它在初始负载下运行
you can send in the option immediate true
你可以立即发送选项true
run the code immediately and then again when search input changes
立即运行代码，然后在搜索输入更改时再次运行
as you can see here a number of events starts at zero
如您所见，许多事件都是从零开始的
as it ran initially
就像它最初运行的那样
and then at works
然后在工作中
as we expect
如我们所料
watch effect
手表效应
only ever takes a single argument which is the call back
只接受一个单独的参数，那就是回电
and watch
看吧
multiple arguments
多个参数
including
包括
reactive object we want to watch
我们要看的反应对象
and options
和选项
we want to configure it
我们要配置它